# AHSANUL HAQUE FARHAN

Portfolio · <a href="https://farhanhaq.com">https://farhanhaq.com</a>
GitHub · <a href="https://github.com/haque-farhan">https://github.com/haque-farhan</a>

Email · farhanhaque.lu@gmail.com · Mobile · +447305559747 LinkedIn · ahsanul-haque-farhan-90052619b

I'm a full-stack developer specializing in frontend and backend development for complex scalable web apps and websites. I have worked with various technologies, most of which are based on PHP and JavaScript. I have maintained, developed and launched multiple projects from scratch, carrying the development of its back end and front-end codebases.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# FEBRUARY 2019 – MARCH 2021 SOFTWARE ENGINEER, TECHNEXT LIMITED

Worked with the core software development team responsible for building software to ensure the best user experience and software security used by millions of users.

- Developed Smart Learning management system, currently using ten thousand students and teachers. Authority can take their exam securely and smoothly.
- Worked on building Laravel REST API and React SPA for social media platforms currently used by 30+ Organizations and thousands of users.
- Developed component module in React based admin template. Currently Most popular template in Bootstrap market.
- Supported design, implementation, and testing of a Civil Laboratory Automation web application written in Vue JS.
- Lead & coordinate a Journal Management web application using CodeIgniter.
- Participated in road map planning of the concerned product.
- Provided support and enhancement on existing websites.

# JUNE 2018 – DECEMBER 2018 INTERNSHIP, APPIFYLAB

Worked on several projects with the team. Most of the projects based on PHP, Laravel, Vue JS.

- Worked on ecommerce web app with the team which using Laravel REST API and Vue SPA.
- Supported design, implementation, and testing of several web applications which is written in Laravel & Vue JS.
- Develop features and fix bugs.
- Involved in client support team.

# **EDUCATION**

**OCTOBER 2021 - PRESENT** 

#### **MSC IN DATA ANALYTICS, DE MONTFORT UNIVERSITY**

Courses · Data Warehouse Design and OLAP, Statistics, Resource Methods

**JANUARY 2015 - DECEMBER 2019** 

#### **BSC IN COMPUTER SCIENCE & ENGINEERING, LEADING UNIVERSITY**

**Courses** · Data Structure, Algorithm, OOP, Database Management System, Web Programming, Software Engineering, Discrete mathematics, Theory of computation and more.

### **SKILLS**

- Front-end: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue, React, Bootstrap. Developed functional product features for Single page web applications. Attentive to UI/UX details and high code quality.
- Back-end: PHP, Laravel, Codelgniter, MySQL Databases. Designed and maintained several web app backends.

# **ACTIVITIES**

- Runner-up in LU Hackathon Contest 2019
- 7<sup>th</sup> in LU Junior Programming Contest
- Former Vice president at Leading University Computer Club (LUCC)
- Former Publicity deputy LU Firefox Club.